Eva vom Baur Hansl Collection of Women's Vocational Materials
Eva vom Baur Hansl Collection of Women's Vocational Materials
- Part time employment
  - College women (Box 14)
  - Comments and arguments (Box 14)
  - Comments, attitudes, and "progress" (Box 14)
  - Discontinuity (Box 14)
  - Fiction (Box 14)
  - Insurance companies (Box 14)
  - Intermittency (Box 14)
  - International (Box 14)
  - Interviews (Box 14)
  - Job search (Box 14)
  - Labor force reports (Box 14)
  - Letters (Box 14)
  - Medicine, women in (Box 14)
  - New York, Denver, Richmond, Milwaukee, Syracuse, San Francisco, Dallas, Providence, Des Moines, Worcester (Box 14)
  - Occupational map (Box 14)
  - Pamphlets (Box 14)
  - Predictions (Box 14)
  - Presentations (Box 14)
  - Projects, miscellaneous (Box 14)
  - Questionnaires (Box 14)
  - Radcliffe on employers (Box 14)
  - Science (Box 14)
  - Social work (Box 14)
  - Status (Box 14)
  - Study of part-time work opportunities for women (Box 14)
  - Teachers (Box 14)
  - Temporaries (Box 14)
  - "Trends in Part-time Employment of College Trained Women" by Eva vB. Hansl (Box 14)
  - Types of jobs (Box 14)
  - Volunteers (Box 14)
  - Woman power (Box 14)
  - Women's part-time and part-year employment patterns in the United States (Box 14)
  - "What They Say" (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 14)
- Roles and attitudes
  - General (Box 14)
  - General, Volume I (1-16), 1948-1964 (Box 14)
  - General, Volume II (17-32), 1948-1964 (Box 14)
  - Attitudes towards women, articles re No.s 1-6 (Box 14)
  - Dilemmas of (Box 14)
  - Education (Box 14)
  - Hartley Y.W.C.A. Scout (Box 14)
  - Hidden Dissuaders (Box 14)
  - Psychological and emotional attitudes toward (Box 14)
  - Radio and television programs re status of women (Box 14)
  - Role expectations of women (Box 14)
  - Social roles of American women (Box 14)
  - Tensions (Box 14)
  - "Women's Role in Our Society" (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 14)
- War Years
  - Index (Box 15)
  - Absenteeism and turnover (Box 15)
  - Armed services (Box 15)
  - Attitudes - women and war jobs (Box 15)
  - Bibliography, women's part in World War II, 1942 (Box 15)
  - Birth rate revolution, 1940-1947 (Box 15)
  - Bryn Mawr Study (Box 15)
  - Case histories (Box 15)
  - Child care
    - Day care (Box 15)
    - "Journey Through Chaos" by Agnes Meyer (Box 15)
  - Child welfare, trends in (Box 15)
  - Children and youth, community planning (Box 15)
  - Children's services - Social Security Act Title V, 1947 (Box 15)
  - Civilian women leaders, conference of, 1943-1950 (Box 15)
  - Community resources (Box 15)
  - Conferences, war years and post-war years (Box 15)
  - Consumer (Box 15)
  - Counseling (Box 16)
  - Draft of women (Box 16)
  - Education
    - General (Box 16)
    - Co-ed (Box 16)
  - Employment
    - General (Box 16)
    - Cutbacks (Box 16)
    - Opportunities (Box 16)
    - Part-time (Box 16)
    - Training (Box 16)
    - Women in industry (Box 16)
  - Employment of women, World War II gains (Box 16)
  - Equal pay (Box 16)
  - Foster home care, Los Angeles, 1944 (Box 16)
  - Health (Box 16)
  - Health and safety (Box 16)
  - Home front (Box 16)
  - Housing (Box 16)
  - Labor reserves (Box 16)
  - Laws, state labor (Box 16)
  - Marshall Plan (Box 16)
  - Mass media (radio) (Box 16)
  - Negro women (Box 16)
  - Nurses and nursing (Box 16)
  - Office of War Information (Box 16)
  - Part-time workers (Box 16)
  - Peace activities and programs for women (Box 16)
  - Peace advocates, women as (Box 16)
  - Peace, drive for (Box 16)
  - Plant and community facilities (Box 16)
  - Politics (Box 16)
  - Projects (Box 16)
  - Psychology of war (Box 16)
  - Recruitment (Box 16)
  - Robert Scheer, "How the United States became involved in Vietnam" (Box 16)
  - Shortages in the professional fields (Box 16)
  - Supervision
    - Women workers (Box 16)
    - Women power (Box 16)
  - Training (Box 16)
  - Unions and labor press, miscellaneous (Box 16)
  - U.S. War Manpower Commission, Women's Auxiliary (Box 16)
  - Veterans (Box 16)
  - Volunteers, war years (Box 16)
  - Wages, war years (Box 16)
  - War correspondents (Box 16)
  - Women in medicine, war years (Box 16)
  - Women in the professions, a war-time survey (Box 16)
  - World War I
    - Clippings (Box 16)
    - Notes and pamphlets (Box 16)
  - Post-war years
    - Armed services, 1945-1956 (Box 16)
    - Armed services counseling (Box 16)
    - Article by Hansl and Hawley (outline) (Box 16)
    - Bibliography (Box 16)
    - Civil defense - decade of defense (Box 16)
    - College women, education and counseling, 1950's (Box 16)
    - Decade of Defense (Box 16)
    - Defense (Box 16)
    - Education to meet war and post war demands (Box 17)
    - G.I. Bill of Rights (Box 17)
    - Occupations (Box 17)
    - Post-war employment (Box 17)
    - Post-war employment plans, U.S. Dept. of Labor, 1946 (Box 17)
    - Reconversion (Box 17)
    - State labor laws (Box 17)
    - Time and leisure (Box 17)
    - Training (Box 17)
    - Trends in post-war employment opportunities for women (history) (Box 17)
    - Unemployment - Connell Case (Box 17)
    - Wages (Box 17)
    - Women workers (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Looking to the future (Box 17)
- Woman power
  - Index (Box 17)
  - Introduction (Box 17)
  - Absenteeism and turnover (Box 17)
  - Advancement (Box 17)
  - Armed services (Box 17)
  - Attitudes toward work
    - Employee (Box 17)
    - Employer (Box 17)
  - Attitudes toward working women
    - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Related material (Box 17)
  - Automation (Box 17)
  - Bibliographies
    - Case histories (Box 17)
    - Material on women workers (Box 17)
  - Business management, women in (Box 17)
  - Business owners, women (Box 17)
  - Church careers and related data (Box 17)
  - Civil Rights Act, Title VII, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (Box 17)
  - Communications industry (Box 17)
  - Computer analysts, operators (Box 17)
  - Conferences, miscellaneous (Box 17)
  - Conferences on women workers (Box 17)
  - Discriminatory practices (Box 17)
  - Earnings (income) and education (Box 17)
  - Earnings, part-time (Box 17)
  - Education (Box 17)
  - Education and woman power (Box 17)
  - Employment, standards for (Box 17)
  - Equal pay for women workers, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Equal pay for women workers, 1 folder (Box 18)
  - Equal Rights Amendment (Box 17)
  - Equal rights for women, miscellaneous (Box 17)
  - Family characteristics of workers, 1957 (Box 17)
  - Feminism (Box 17)
  - Finance for the working woman (Box 17)
  - Government jobs, appointive and elective (Box 17)
  - Government jobs, civil service (Box 18)
  - Health care for women workers (Box 18)
  - Home industries (Box 18)
  - Hours, working (Box 18)
  - Industry, women in (Box 18)
  - Intermittency and returnees (Box 18)
  - Job seeking
    - Resumes, A. Cronin, 1962 (Box 18)
    - Techniques (Box 18)
  - Job status trends and standards (Box 18)
  - Jobs, first, of college women (Box 18)
  - Jury duty, for women (Box 18)
  - Labor relations bibliography, Cornell University (Box 18)
  - Law
    - Equal Rights Amendment (Box 19)
    - Fair Labor Standards Act (Box 19)
    - License requirements for various occupations (Box 19)
    - Minimum wage legislation and studies (Box 19)
    - Minimum wage provisions (Box 19)
    - Women workers and (Box 19)
  - Manpower, Challenge of the 1960's (U.S.D.L. Study), 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Maternity benefits for women workers (Box 19)
  - Migrant labor data and legislation (Box 19)
  - Mobility (Box 19)
  - Mobility and the family (Box 19)
  - Mobilization of women (Box 19)
  - Moonlighting (Box 19)
  - Motivation to work (Box 19)
  - National Manpower Council (Box 19)
  - Negro women (Box 19)
  - Nepotism (Box 19)
  - Night work, New York State Dept of Labor Reports, 1941-1948 (Box 19)
  - Obstacles for women (Box 19)
  - Overworked and underworked women (Box 19)
  - Part-time employment (Box 19)
  - Predictions (Box 19)
  - Professional woman power (Box 19)
  - Public Policy towards married women's work (Box 19)
  - Recruitment of women (Box 19)
  - Replacement womanpower (Box 19)
  - Returnees, includes case histories (Box 19)
  - Roster, American science, manpower, 1964 (Box 19)
  - Satisfaction (Box 19)
  - Self-employed, how to be; "Hobby Becomes Business" (Box 19)
  - Shortages
    - General - womanpower (Box 19)
    - Teachers - womanpower (Box 19)
  - Surveys, womanpower (Box 19)
  - Tables of Working Life of Women (Box 19)
  - Temporaries (Box 19)
  - Tenure (Box 19)
  - Training (Box 19)
  - Trends in employment (Box 19)
  - Trends in employment opportunities (Box 19)
  - Unemployment insurance compensation (Box 19)
  - Unemployment of working women (Box 19)
  - Unions (Box 19)
  - Unions and the working woman (Box 20)
  - Upgrading womanpower (Box 20)
  - Utilization (Box 20)
  - Waste of educated womanpower (Box 20)
  - Wealth (Box 20)
  - White collar workers (Box 20)
  - Work experience (Box 20)
  - Working mothers (Box 20)
  - Working wives (Box 20)
- General files
  - Index (Box 20)
  - Achievement, Women of (Box 20)
  - Affluence (Box 20)
  - Age statistics (Box 20)
  - Aging, miscellaneous (Box 20)
  - Aging, organizations in the field of (Box 20)
  - Agriculture, U.S. Department of (Box 20)
  - Air pollution (Box 20)
  - Alcohol (Box 20)
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science, Annals of, 1947 (Box 20)
  - American life, women in (Box 20)
  - American Personnel and Guidance Association, Members Publications (Box 20)
  - Anthropology (Box 20)
  - Archives, women's
    - General (Box 20)
    - Radcliffe (Box 20)
  - Art (Box 20)
  - Atlanta (Georgia) club women (Box 20)
  - Automobile (Box 20)
  - Aviation (Box 20)
  - Awards and honors (Box 20)
  - Banking (Box 20)
  - Bibliographies
    - General, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - American history (Box 20)
    - Industrial and labor relations, Cornell University Library (Box 20)
    - Periods in US history (Box 20)
    - Special (Box 21)
    - Women (Box 21)
  - Blind (Box 21)
  - Book outlines (Box 21)
  - Book reviews, current (Box 21)
  - Books (Box 21)
  - Books by women (Box 21)
  - Canada (Box 21)
  - Career, 1935-1940 (Box 21)
  - Cartoons (Box 21)
  - Case histories
    - General (Box 21)
    - Dual jobs (Box 21)
    - Math and science (Box 22)
    - Part-time (Box 22)
    - Special (Box 22)
  - Censorship, general (Box 22)
  - Census
    - Household, families, workers (Box 22)
    - Population (Box 22)
    - Reports (Box 22)
  - China (Box 22)
  - Churches (Box 22)
  - Civic and city club, women (Box 22)
  - Civil Rights Act (Box 22)
  - Civil service, England, women in (Box 22)
  - Club women (Box 22)
  - Collectors (Box 22)
  - College education, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - College professors (Box 22)
  - Community projects (Box 22)
  - Congresswomen (Box 22)
  - Consumers, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Consumers, women as (Box 22)
  - Crime, women and (Box 22)
  - Dancers (Box 22)
  - Defense (Box 22)
  - Defense, home (Box 22)
  - Defense training (Box 22)
  - Democracy (Box 22)
  - Democarcy and freedom (Box 22)
  - Drugs (Box 22)
  - Economics (Box 22)
  - Education (Box 22)
  - Educational enrichment programs for culturally deprived groups (Box 22)
  - Embezzlers (Box 22)
  - Employment (Box 22)
  - Equal rights, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Equal rights amendments and treaties (Box 23)
  - Equality (Box 23)
  - Euthenics - Vassar College, 1923-1940 (Box 23)
  - Explorers (Box 23)
  - Facts and figures (Box 23)
  - Fatigue (Box 23)
  - Fellowships for women (Box 23)
  - Feminism, 1935-1937 (Box 23)
  - Finance (Box 23)
  - Finance, as it affects women (Box 23)
  - Floods (Box 23)
  - Food (Box 23)
  - Founders (Box 23)
  - Four Hundred, women of the (Box 23)
  - France (Box 23)
  - Free speech (Box 23)
  - Freedom Train documents on women, 1947 (Box 23)
  - Garden (Box 23)
  - Geneva - "Service d'Archives" (Box 23)
  - Germany, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Glasses (Box 23)
  - Grandmothers (Box 23)
  - Great Society (L.B.J.) (Box 23)
  - Handicap (Box 23)
  - Health, 1940s; 2 folders (Box 23)
  - High school girls (Box 23)
  - History (Box 23)
  - Home (Box 23)
  - Horticulturalist (Box 23)
  - Household arts (Box 23)
  - Housework (Box 23)
  - Housing (Box 23)
  - Human relations (Box 23)
  - Human resources
    - General (Box 23)
    - Conservation (Box 23)
  - Indian-American women (Box 23)
  - Indians, American and foreign (Box 23)
  - Industry (Box 23)
  - Inequality (Box 23)
  - Institute of Women's Professional Relations
    - Directory of institutions concerned with training
      - Art in industry, 1940 (Box 23)
      - Business and industry, 1947 (Box 23)
      - Health, 1936; 1945 (Box 23)
      - Health and the arts, 1936; 1945 (Box 24)
    - Fellowships and other aids for advanced work, 1930; 1940 (Box 24)
    - Occupations for college women, 1929 (Box 24)
    - Opportunities in the public service, 1940 (Box 25)
    - War and post-war employment and its demands for educational adjustments (Box 25)
    - War demands for trained personnel, 1942 (Box 25)
    - Work opportunities in American fashion design, 1941 (Box 25)
  - Insurance (Box 25)
  - Insurance, Social Security, Medicare, private policies (Box 25)
  - Interest survey (Box 25)
  - International material (Box 25)
  - Internships (Box 25)
  - Inventions (Box 25)
  - Inventors (Box 25)
  - Jewish women (Box 25)
  - Job opportunities: Girl Scout recruitment (Box 25)
  - Journalism, clippings, notes; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Jurors (Box 25)
  - Jury duty (Box 25)
  - Kindergartens (Box 25)
  - Labor (Box 25)
  - Labor laws, New York State (Box 25)
  - Lathrop, Julia (Box 25)
  - Latin America (Box 25)
  - Law, women and (Box 25)
  - Laws, state, of special value to women (Box 25)
  - Lawyers, jurors, and jurists, women as (Box 25)
  - League of Nations (Box 25)
  - Legislation, Federal (Box 25)
  - Leisure
    - General (Box 25)
    - T.C. discussion groups (Box 25)
  - Leisure time workers (Box 25)
  - Leisure time studies (Box 25)
  - Living biographies (Box 25)
  - Longevity (Box 25)
  - Lucy Stone League (Box 25)
  - Manners (Box 25)
  - Marriage (Box 25)
  - Marriage consultation (Box 25)
  - Mass media (Box 25)
  - Medicaid (Box 25)
  - Medicare (Box 25)
  - Medicine (Box 25)
  - Medicine, women doctors (Box 25)
  - Men in women's sphere (Box 26)
  - Mental health (Box 26)
  - Merchandising (Box 26)
  - Mexico (Box 26)
  - Middle class (Box 26)
  - Middle years (Box 26)
  - Minimum wage law (Box 26)
  - Models (Box 26)
  - Mortality (Box 26)
  - Mothers (Box 26)
  - Mothers and daughters (Box 26)
  - National Service Corps. (Box 26)
  - Negro (Box 26)
  - Negro affairs (Box 26)
  - New Jersey Writers Project (Box 26)
  - New York State Department of Commerce (Box 26)
  - Nursery schools (Box 26)
  - Obituaries (Box 26)
  - Organizations, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Patriotic organizations (Box 26)
  - Peace (Box 26)
  - Peace Corps volunteers (Box 26)
  - Pension funds (Box 26)
  - Perkins, Frances (Box 26)
  - Poetry (Box 26)
  - Poets (Box 26)
  - Political life, womanpower (Young report) (Box 26)
  - Political organizations, women's (Box 26)
  - Politics and government, general (Box 26)
  - Politics, women in (Box 26)
  - Pollution, general (Box 26)
  - Population
    - General (Box 26)
    - Growth and control of (Box 26)
    - Old age (Box 26)
  - Post offices and communications (Box 26)
  - Posture (Box 26)
  - Poverty, economic opportunity profile (Box 26)
  - Poverty profiles (American Association of University Women) (Box 26)
  - Problems of a changing population, 1938 (Box 26)
  - Professional, technical and kindred Workers
    - Letters, Dr. Ethel Alpenfels (Box 26)
    - National Science Foundation Report (Box 26)
    - Special fields (Box 26)
  - Profiles, general (Box 26)
  - Providers (Box 26)
  - Psychology (Box 26)
  - Public health (Box 26)
  - Puritan women (Box 26)
  - Quotes (Box 26)
  - Radio, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Railroads (Box 26)
  - Refugee women, displaced persons (Box 27)
  - Rehabilitation (Box 27)
  - Religion (Box 27)
  - Religion, women in (Box 27)
  - Research
    - IV Shively Wessiervelt (Box 27)
    - V Research Survey - teachers' research letters - Hawkes and Brumbaugh (Box 27)
    - VI
  - Retirement planning and resources, general (Box 27)
  - Richest women (Box 27)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Box 27)
  - Royalty (Box 27)
  - Rural (Box 27)
  - Russia (Box 27)
  - Russian women (Box 27)
  - Safety, general (Box 27)
  - Scandinavian women (Box 27)
  - Science
    - General (Box 27)
    - Letters, National Conference on the Participation of Women in Science (Box 27)
  - Sea (Box 28)
  - Sects (Box 28)
  - Service Bureau for Women's Organization, 1955-1966; annual reports; 6 folders (Box 28)
  - Sex, general (Box 28)
  - Single women and men (Box 28)
  - Social change and forces affecting it (Box 28)
  - Social Security
    - General (Box 28)
    - Widows (Box 28)
  - Social trends (Box 28)
  - Social welfare, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - South, women in the (Box 28)
  - Status, general, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Streamlined grandmothers (Box 28)
  - Suburbia, general (Box 28)
  - Suffrage
    - General (Box 28)
    - Nationality (Box 28)
    - Smith Sisters (Box 28)
    - Women's in the United States (Box 28)
  - Taxes and women's interests (Box 28)
  - Uncommon women (Box 28)
  - United Nations
    See also International and foreign women: United Nations
    - Commission on Status of Women (Box 28)
    - News stories re. women (Box 28)
    - Publications re. women (Box 28)
    - "Women in the World Today" (Box 28)
  - Unsung women (Box 28)
  - Virginia Writers Project (Box 28)
  - Vocations and vocational training, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Voters (Box 28)
  - War (Box 28)
  - War veterans, women (Box 28)
  - War, women and (Box 28)
  - Wealth (Box 29)
  - Wealth, women of (Box 29)
  - Wife of... (Box 29)
  - Womanpower utilization, letters (Box 29)
  - Women (Box 29)
  - Women and their money (Box 29)
  - Women at work, 5 folders (Box 29)
  - Women in action, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Women in Dictionary of American Biography (Box 29)
  - Women in modern America - "Emergence" (Box 29)
  - Women, past and present (Box 29)
  - Women, status of, general (Box 29)
  - Women's Charter (Box 29)
  - Women's clubs (Box 29)
  - Women's contribution to national development (Box 29)
  - Women's courts (Box 29)
  - Women's rights (Box 29)
  - Work and marriage (Box 29)
  - World's Fairs, women and (Box 29)
  - Writers, women (Box 29)
  - Young adults and the YWCA (Box 29)
  - Youth
    - General (Box 29)
    - Counseling (Box 29)
    - Culture (Box 29)
    - Delinquency (Box 29)
    - Draft (Box 29)
    - Education (Box 29)
    - Employment (Box 30)
    - Finances (Box 30)
    - Health (Box 30)
    - Law, juvenile court (Box 30)
    - National Service Act (Box 30)
    - Organizations (Box 30)
    - Part-time (Box 30)
    - Revolt (Box 30)
    - Sex (Box 30)
    - Social activities (Box 30)
    - Suburbia (Box 30)
    - Volunteers for youth (Box 30)
    - War years (Box 30)
    - Youth and work in New York City (Box 30)
    - Youth as volunteers (Box 30)
    - "Youth goes into action" (Box 30)
    - Youth power (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous, historical background (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous, general (Box 30)
- Published Material
  - "Insider's Newsletter", Sept. 20, 1960-April 24, 1967; undated (Box 31)
  - Newspaper clippings, A-Z by topic
    - Abortion - Awards (Box 31)
    - Babies - College (Box 31)
    - Community Centers - Discrimination (Box 31)
    - Divorce - Education (Box 31)
    - Employment - Feminine Principle (Box 31)
    - Government and Politics - Human Resources (Box 31)
    - Illegitimacy - Libraries (Box 31)
    - Marriage - Mothers Working (Box 31)
    - Narcotics - Poverty Program (Box 31)
    - Projections - Secretaries (Box 31)
    - Sex Education - Teachers (Box 31)
    - Technological Change - Wives (Box 31)
    - Women (misc.) - Youth (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944; 1948,; 1950,; 1951,; 1953-1954,; 1960,; 1964-1966; 9 folders (Box 31)
    - Biographies and obituaries, 1966 (Box 32)
    - Clippings, 1967 (Box 32)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 32)
    - General newspaper clippings, 1967 (Box 32)
    - Unsorted clippings (Box 32)
  - Pamphlets
    - On Education
      - 1947-1964, 9 folders (Box 32)
      - 1965-1966, undated (Box 33)
    - On Labor, 1941-1950; 1952-1966; 11 folders (Box 33)
    - On The atatus of women, 1963-1966 (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous, 1940-1963; 3 folders (Box 34)
  - United States Government, 1966-1967 (Box 34)
- Miscellaneous
  - Unsorted material (Box 34)
  - Unsorted material (Box 35)